It's scrumdidilyumptious!
Willy Wonka & the Chocolate Factory is a family,
fantasy, comedy film directed by Mel Stuart.
When eccentric candy man Willy Wonka promises a lifetime supply of sweets and a tour of his chocolate factory to
five lucky kids, penniless Charlie Bucket seeks the golden ticket that will make him a winner.
Willy Wonka, played by Gene Wilder.
Charlie Bucket, played by Peter Ostrum.
Grandpa Joe, played by Jack Albertson.
Augustus Gloop, played by Michael Bollner.
Veruca Salt, played by Julie Dawn Cole.
Violet Beauregarde, played by Denise Nickerson.
Willy Wonka & the Chocolate Factory is a 1971 American musical fantasy film directed by Mel Stuart from
a screenplay by Roald Dahl, based on his 1964 novel Charlie and the Chocolate Factory.
It stars Gene Wilder as chocolatier Willy Wonka.
The film tells the story of a poor child named Charlie Bucket (Peter Ostrum) who, upon finding a Golden Ticket in a chocolate
bar, wins the chance to visit Willy Wonka's chocolate factory along with four other children from around the world.
Filming took place in Munich from August to November 1970.
Dahl was credited with writing the film's screenplay; however, David
Seltzer was brought in to do an uncredited rewrite.
Against Dahl's wishes, changes were made to the story, and other
decisions made by the director led Dahl to disown the film.
The musical numbers were written by Leslie Bricusse and Anthony Newley while
Walter Scharf arranged and conducted the orchestral score.
Willy Wonka & the Chocolate Factory was released in the United
States on June 30, 1971, by Paramount Pictures.
While the film received positive reviews from critics, it was not a major financial
success, earning just $4 million by the end of its original run.
It received a nomination for Best Original Score at the 44th Academy Awards and Wilder was nominated for
Best Performance in a Motion Picture – Comedy or Musical at the 29th Golden Globe Awards.
The film also introduced the song "The Candy Man", which
went on to be recorded by Sammy Davis Jr.
and become a popular hit.
Willy Wonka & the Chocolate Factory has since become highly popular
through television airings and home video sales.
In 2014, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress, as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of factory worker, factory,
based on novel or book, chocolate, candy.
The tone is lighthearted.